<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--
  Content Structure: 

  <entry>
    <type></type>
    <question>
    </question>
    <answer>
    </answer>
  </entry>
-->
<entries>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Noun
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Effort, Factor
⏵ Time, Cost, Scope
⏵ Peer, Colleague, Teammate
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Verb
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Prepare, Construct, Develop
⏵ Collaborate, Coordinate, Manage, Coach, Lead, Drive
⏵ Suggest, Recommend
⏵ Publish, Subscribe
⏵ Schedule / Hold a meeting
⏵ Escalate to _____
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Keyword</type>
    <question>
Adjective
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Loose Coupled, Tightly Coupled, Internal, External
⏵ Advantage, Disadvantage, Benefit, Drawback
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Key Sentences to Introduce Yourself at a Job Interview in English
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Good morning/afternoon. My name is ______ and I want to thank you for this opportunity.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and it’s a pleasure for me to be here.
⏵ Good morning/afternoon. I’m _______ and I want to thank you for taking me into consideration for this position.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and I’m glad you called me because I really want to work for this company.
⏵ Hi! My name is ________ and I’m here because I think I have the profile you’re looking for.
⏵ Hello! My name is _______ and first of all I want to congratulate you for making this company capable of offering a top quality service!
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Asking Someone to Repeat a Question
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I’m sorry. Would you please repeat the question?
⏵ Excuse me, I didn’t hear you. Can you please say that again?
⏵ Would you please say that again?
⏵ Could you please repeat the question and speak a little bit harder?
⏵ Sorry, I didn’t understand you. Could you please say that again?
⏵ I’m sorry, I didn’t hear the last part. Can you repeat it, please?
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Emphasizing Your Strengths
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I think I’m the right choice for this job because I know how to…
⏵ My (mention a set of skills relevant for the job) will allow me to do this easily.
⏵ I’m very good at ________ and that’s why I think I’ll be able to handle this position. (Fill the blank space with the one you consider is your best strength.)
⏵ I’d love to work here because I _______.
⏵ I think my ________, my _________ and my __________ make me perfect for this job.
⏵ I can say my top 3 skills are: ________, _________ and _________.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Thanking the Interviewer at the End of the Interview in English
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ Thank you very much for your time. I’ll be waiting for your call!
⏵ I want you to know that I’m very thankful for this.
⏵ Before I leave I want to thank you for the opportunity. I hope we see each other again soon!
⏵ I wanted to thank you before I leave. I hope I have the profile you’re looking for.
⏵ It was a pleasure meeting you and then again I want to thank you for having me here!
⏵ I want to thank you one last time and I’ll be expecting your call!
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Example</type>
    <question>
Some other sentences for a job interview in English 
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ I’ve been looking for this position for a long time.
⏵ I love the idea of working here because I enjoy _______.
⏵ This is what I always wanted to do and I know I can do it very well.
⏵ I’m glad I was recommended by _______ for this position!
⏵ I’m glad I saw this job post because I’m very excited about the idea of working for this company.
⏵ You can expect nothing but proficiency and excellent results if you hire me.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++⏵ ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
</entries>
