<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--
  Content Structure: 

  <entry>
    <type></type>
    <question>
    </question>
    <answer>
    </answer>
  </entry>
-->
<entries>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Performance</type>
    <question>
Troubleshoot why the internet is slow
    </question>
    <answer>
Ask Questions:

⏵ Is it slow on all devices?
⏵ Did it start happening recently?

Possible Reasons:

⏵ Too many people using the internet.
⏵ Old router or modem.
⏵ Something big is downloading or streaming.

Troubleshooting Steps:

⏵ Check connection: Use Ethernet cable to see if Wi-Fi is the problem.
⏵ Speed test: Use a website to check internet speed.
⏵ Check devices: Look for damage on router or modem.
⏵ See what's using internet: Look for apps or devices using a lot of internet.
⏵ Change Wi-Fi channel: If too many Wi-Fi networks are nearby.
⏵ Talk to ISP: Ask if they have issues or are doing maintenance.

Linux Commands:

⏵ Ping Test: Check connection to a website. ( ping google.com )
⏵ Speed Test: Use a command-line tool like speedtest-cli ( speedtest-cli )
⏵ Check Network Usage: Identify what's using your bandwidth. ( iftop )
⏵ Wi-Fi Signal: Check Wi-Fi signal strength. ( iwconfig )
⏵ Compare with other devices or setting
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Protocol</type>
    <question>
What port does ftp, sftp, ssh, telnet use?
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ FTP (File Transfer Protocol): Uses port 21 for command and control (sending commands and receiving responses). 
⏵ FTP (File Transfer Protocol): Uses port 20 for data transfer (transferring files).
⏵ SSH (Secure Shell): Uses port 22 for secure data communication, remote command-line login, remote command execution, and other secure network services.
⏵ Telnet: Uses port 23 for unencrypted (and therefore insecure) network communication; used for remote login services.
⏵ SFTP (SSH File Transfer Protocol): Also uses port 22, as it is an extension of SSH and provides secure file transfer capabilities.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Protocol</type>
    <question>
Explain SSL, TLS, HTTP, HTTPS
    </question>
    <answer>
⏵ SSL and TLS are cryptographic protocols that secure data in transit. TLS is the newer, more secure version.
⏵ HTTP is the protocol for transferring web content, but it does not encrypt data, making it vulnerable to interception.
⏵ HTTPS combines HTTP with TLS/SSL encryption, ensuring that data transferred between the web browser and server is secure and private.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Concept</type>
    <question>
TCP Three-Way Handshake
What are the three TCP connection packets names? 
What are the packets sent in a TCP connection?
    </question>
    <answer>
Connection Establishment (Three-Way Handshake):
⏵ SYN (Synchronize): Sent by the client to the server to initiate a TCP connection, carrying a sequence number for synchronization.
⏵ SYN-ACK (Synchronize-Acknowledgment): Sent by the server in response to the SYN packet, acknowledging the client's SYN (with an ACK) and sending its own SYN.
⏵ ACK (Acknowledgment): Sent by the client in response to the server's SYN-ACK, acknowledging the server's SYN.

Data Transfer (Maintaining the Connection):
⏵ Data Packets: After the connection is established, data packets are sent between the client and server. Each data packet sent requires an acknowledgment packet in response to confirm receipt.
⏵ Acknowledgment Packets: These are sent to confirm the receipt of data packets.

Connection Termination:
⏵ FIN (Finish): Either party (client or server) can initiate the termination process by sending a FIN packet, indicating it has no more data to send.
⏵ ACK: The receiving party responds with an ACK to acknowledge the FIN packet.
⏵ FIN: The receiving party then sends its own FIN packet, indicating it's also ready to close the connection.
⏵ ACK: The initiating party responds with an ACK to acknowledge the final FIN, completing the four-way termination process.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
  <entry>
    <type>Concept</type>
    <question>
What are Layer 4 and Layer 7 in OSI model?
    </question>
    <answer>
Layer 4 - Transport Layer:
⏵ Responsible for end-to-end communication and error recovery.
⏵ Where TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) operates, providing reliable data transfer.

Layer 7 - Application Layer:
⏵ The layer closest to the end user.
⏵ It allows access to network services that support applications.
⏵ Examples include HTTP for web browsing, SMTP for email.
    </answer>
  </entry>
  <!-- ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ -->
</entries>
